[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
Mama! Mama!
Arnaldo almost killed you!
Emilia tried to murder you!
The next time something
like this happens, remember,
I'll be the one
to take the bullet for you.
I'm the mayor of this place!
Why are you keeping me in here?!
[Julio] I want Arnaldo out of
that stinking rathole
as soon as possible.
Please tell me.
Who was behind all that bedlam?
Papa, isn't it obvious?
It was Ivy and Diego
who staged everything
to bring Arnaldo down.
So, if we are to hit back at anyone,
I want to make sure
we hit the right target.
That's Arthur Vergara,
one of Camia Cruz's witnesses.
I already regret what I did to Carlotta.
-What more do you want?
-This isn't enough!
I want your conscience to eat at you.
Send my regards to Emilia.
Given the fact that she wanted me killed…
[Emilia] I wouldn't be surprised
if that woman slandered me to my son.
That's why Arnaldo's so mad at me.
And he almost killed me!
We should get the head of the snake.
We should kill her.
-Ivy Aguas is better off dead.
-Do it.
Tell me what I can do to help you.
Give me Ivy. I'm begging you.
Please escort Ivy Aguas to hell.
And give my regards to the devil too.
Yes, ma'am.
[car engine starts]
How exciting.
[tense music playing]
What's going on here?
Congressman.
Mrs. Emilia and Col. Sanggano
ordered us to kill Ivy Aguas.
[chuckles]
Sorry to disappoint you, children,
but there won't be any bloodshed today.
I need Ms. Aguas, and I need her alive.
Understood, Congressman.
Yes, ma'am.
Make sure these papers are all--
Ms. Ivy, you have to see this.
The Ardientes' men are here.
[tense music playing]
What are you doing here, Congressman?
We need to talk, Ms. Aguas.
[car doors open]
That's as far as you go, Congressman.
You and your army are not welcome here.
So, what did you want to discuss?
And make it quick too.
Okay, let's cut to the chase.
I'm here to make you an offer, Ivy.
An offer?
A hundred million pesos.
Plus, any government position you want.
[laughing]
Seriously?
Yes.
And in exchange?
Get back together with my grandson.
Arnaldo needs you.
And if you really meant it
when you said you loved him…
And, if you really had nothing
to do with the incident…
You'll take care of him,
help him get back on his feet,
and make him feel loved
like you said you would.
There's no way I'm getting back
with the man who killed my Nanny Carlotta!
If you really love someone,
you can forgive them no matter
the mistakes they might make.
Unless the whispers and rumors are true
that you're betraying us
and siding with the enemy.
In that case, there's nothing
else to be discussed.
But then again, you know me.
You know what I'm capable of.
I can have you obliterated
from the face of this earth!
And, I'll let all your loved ones witness
you experiencing an agonizing death.
Ivy, Ivy…
You're courting a war
that you're not prepared for.
Or, have thought of,
even in your wildest dreams.
So please, don't push me against the wall!
Don't test me.
Do you need an answer now?
I'll think about it.
Fair enough.
But I won't wait forever.
Remember, someone in my family
desperately wants to see you dead.
And, I'm the only one
who can protect you from her.
At the end of the day,
you need me more than I need you.
And I do hope you make the right
and wise decision.
[tense music playing]
You're so cute, Congressman.
Very amusing.
-Well, how was your errand?
-Ma'am…
Why are you with our men, Papa?
Well, who did you expect to find anyway?
Ivy's corpse, maybe?
Ivy Aguas' funeral is postponed
until further notice.
Huh?! But why?!
My secretary will inform you
of the latest developments.
In the meantime, have a nice day.
-Auntie?
-Diego?
Anna, where's Ms. Camia?
Ms. Camia, Diego's here!
-Diego.
-Auntie.
Ivy's asking me to get you.
We're going to meet her.
Really?
-Wait, right now?
-Yes, right now.
Okay. I'll go get changed.
Where does she plan to meet us?
She didn't tell me.
So get dressed, Auntie.
Okay, I'll get dressed.
I'm so excited to see my daughter!
Wait for me.
Diego.
Hey, what are you two waiting for?
-We're coming too?
-Of course.
Ivy wants to see all of us.
Hey.
-Lily!
-Mom.
[soft music playing]
Anna.
Jepoy.
I'm happy that we're all together.
Now, I want to thank you all.
My plan was successful
because of all of you.
Jepoy, Diego…
Thank you so much.
You did everything to protect me.
We achieved a great victory
by defeating Arnaldo,
but we aren't done yet.
That was just the beginning.
But for now, we'll celebrate.
I missed you, Lily.
I missed you too, Mom.
[Emilia screaming]
[sobbing]
Emilia, what's going on?!
That's enough, already.
-Let go of me!
-What's going on?
Nothing! You don't care, right?!
Nothing's going on!
Wait…
If you're mad, don't take it out on me.
Why not? What are you
going to do about it?
I'm always the one fighting for us.
You can't even stand up
to Papa on your own!
That's why this is all you can do!
What are you trying to prove?
That I'm a loser?
I need a man who is my equal,
and that obviously isn't you!
Well then, let's split up already!
You know?
I just realized, I never had
the courage to say that to you.
Yes! I'm filing an annulment.
We're through.
Wait, Emilia. Why are you like this today?
Why are you acting so tough?
Do I already have a replacement?
Is it Jaguar?
Don't wait for my answer.
You might not like it.
[dramatic music playing]
[sobs]
[pensive music playing]
Diego, I need to talk
to Arthur immediately.
Arthur, we need your help.
Ivy needs your help.
Diego, I'm making changes to my plans.
I'll broadcast Arnaldo's confession
to all of Ardiente.
I'll make sure your plans succeed.
Even if it costs me my life,
I won't let anything happen to you.
[explosion]
Aren't you done yet?
Arnaldo's reciting his vows.
We're running out of time!
Hang on, Diego.
I'm waiting for the right moment.
Hey! Diego!
Stop the wedding!
Diego.
I'll be repeating what I said earlier,
but I want to tell you
in a more personal way…
Thank you.
Thank you for keeping your promise to me
that you'd help my plans succeed.
I hope you'll be with me
till the very end.
["Hindi Kita Iiwan" by Sam Milby playing]
Thank you, Diego.
Look.
Raul.
Where's your wife?
She's gone, Papa.
Emilia left me.
Are you kidding me?
No, Papa. It's true.
Whoa.
For real? She left you?
For what reason? Why?
[chuckles]
Don't tell me it's because
you've been unfaithful again.
Because if that's the case,
she should have left you years ago.
So, that can't be the reason.
No, I haven't cheated on her.
You didn't cheat on her?
[laughs]
No…
It's the other way around?
Emilia cheated on you?
She's the cheater now?
[laughing]
Finally!
Finally, my daughter
does something good in her life!
Something that I can applaud her for!
Emilia, wherever you are, congratulations!
This is wonderful!
[laughs]
Oh wait, Raul.
How does it feel to be given
a dose of your own medicine?
Hmm?
Oh, okay.
You don't have to answer me.
Anyway…
Just keep it up, my son.
Who knows?
You might die ahead of me.
[grunts]
[splashes]
Diego, you okay there?
Is it gone?
It got away.
By the way, thank you.
For protecting and watching over Ivy.
But let me tell you this.
Don't get too comfy.
Because if you hurt her,
not only will you get it from me…
I'll take her from you.
She's in good hands with me.
Don't worry.
I hope so, bro. I hope so.
You can trust me on that.
[upbeat music playing]
Did you get it?
Did you?
Yeah.
[upbeat music continues]
No, you didn't.
See, bro…
Just because you have something
doesn't mean it's yours.
You need to secure it.
Get it?
-There's so much food!
-That's right! Wow!
Oh.
Look at that, Anna!
Jepoy caught such a huge fish!
You're right! That is huge!
I caught everything here.
Jepoy just took it from me.
Why did you have to fight over one fish
when there are
so many fishes in the river?
Just like Lily. People fight over her.
What?
What did you say?
[chuckles] Nothing, Auntie.
I was just asking where Lily went.
We should call her so we can start eating.
That's right. Where is my daughter?
I'm hungry.
Auntie, I think this is done.
This is ready.
Where did Lily go?
[soft music playing]
Ivy.
I'm sorry. You got shot because of me.
I wasn't careful enough.
Arnaldo got a hold of my gun.
You were hit by my own bullet.
And you know what? You were right.
I shouldn't have let my anger
get the best of me.
I almost ruined your plans.
You were right and I was wrong.
Jepoy, you don't have to apologize.
Truth is, I'm at fault too,
because I didn't tell you anything.
I kept my plans from you.
But, just like what I said earlier,
thank you for doing everything
you can to protect me.
So please never blame yourself
because you've done so much for me, Jepoy.
And those scars…
They will forever be there.
I'm sorry.
This is nothing, Ivy.
I'm willing to do everything for you.
Uh…
Ivy, Jepoy,
everyone's been looking for you.
The food's ready.
Okay.
Ivy.
Don't get too comfy.
Just because you have something
doesn't mean it's yours.
If you hurt her, not only
will you get it from me…
I'll take her from you.
Ivy, we'll go ahead.
Thanks for inviting us here.
I'll let you take Anna
to the airport tomorrow, okay?
Leave it to us.
Be careful on your way to Singapore, okay?
Thanks for everything, Lily.
[soft music playing]
I'm grateful to you and Diego.
You two gave justice
to Nanny Carlotta's death.
I'll miss you guys.
Anna, we'll miss you more.
It's so hard to say goodbye
when we're already this close,
Auntie Camia.
Anna, don't be sad.
When this is all over, I promise
we'll be together again.
That we'll all be happy again.
Just like old times.
Take care in Singapore.
You should go.
It's getting late. Take care.
Thank you, Auntie.
Anna!
[sniffles]
We'll all be together again.
It's a promise.
Remember that.
It's all right. Go.
[car engine starts]
[exhales]
[party music playing]
Mrs. Emilia.
[pensive music playing]
[sensual music playing]
Emilia.
What are you doing here?
My husband and I aren't together anymore.
Do you still love your husband, Emilia?
I need a man who is my equal,
and that obviously isn't you!
Well then, let's split up already!
Emilia, I'd love to marry you again.
Yes! I'll marry you again. Over and over.
Yes.
I still love him.
[somber music playing]
[sobbing]
What am I doing?
Mom, it's late. Let's head in.
Lily, I don't think
I want this night to end.
I want us to still be together.
Mom, all things, whether good or bad,
have to come to an end.
And that's why I'll cherish
this night to the fullest.
Like I told you…
The fight has just begun.
I'm not through with the Ardientes.
So, I don't know when I'll see you again.
Or, when I can be with you like this.
I won't let us be separated ever again.
Never.
[instrumental music playing]
[scoffs]
Judge Villalobos,
you're the one handling
my grandson's case, yes?
Well then, you know what to do.
Good.
[foreboding music playing]
[whimpers]
Sign this.
Excuse me. What's this?
-What's that, Papa?
-I don't know.
[clears throat]
Really? Now?
Annulment papers?
Annulment?
Are you sure about that, Emilia?
Do you think you can just leave me?
Can you even live without me?
What do you think, Raul?
I think you should reconsider this.
You're just angry.
I have thought it over, Raul.
And my decision is final.
So, sign it.
Papa!
What are you doing?!
What am I doing? I'm tearing this!
Listen!
Save your domestic drama
for some other time.
Think of your son!
Your son needs you all the more right now!
And I don't want the public to know
that this family is falling apart!
Let's behave like a normal family.
Go ahead. Eat!
Thank you so much for everything.
Miss Loring, Mr. Pandoy,
Marlon, Mr. Fernan…
Diego.
I'll miss you all.
I just hope everything here
will turn out well.
We hope so too.
[reporter] In a stunning turn of events,
charges against Mayor Arnaldo Torillo
were dismissed as the court
granted his petition of…
Mr. Marlon, Mr. Diego,
you should see this!
…despite his confession
being shown to the public.
He was not caught in the act
committing the crime.
Therefore, it is illegal to detain
the Mayor of Poblacion Ardiente
by his people.
How could they get away with this?!
[reporter] Congressman, any statement
regarding your grandson's dismissal?
Well, this isn't just a victory
for our family.
This is a victory for
our country's justice system.
This proves that justice is equal for all
and that they continue to protect…
the rights of innocent people
like my grandson.
For the record…
We aren't bad people.
We aren't the enemy.
We are victims
of unfortunate circumstances.
Geez! They freed that bastard of a mayor!
Mr. Mayor, can I have a word with you?
Any messages for Ms. Ivy Aguas?
[people chanting in background]
Viva Ardiente!
He's crazy…
[people chanting in background]
Viva Ardiente!
[tense music playing]
[pensive music playing]
Anna.
Come on. I'll drive you to the airport.
Anna?
Jepoy, are you content?
Are you content with the fact
that Nanny Carlota's murderer
served only a few weeks in jail?
Was that enough punishment for his crime?
Jepoy, is that what you call justice?!
Anna, we won't stop
until all the Ardientes
get the punishment they deserve!
No. I will no longer count on anyone else
to help me find justice for Nanny Carlota!
Anna, listen to me…
You aren't safe here.
I have to take you to the airport now.
You had a deal with Ivy, remember?
Listen to me.
-No.
-Let's go--
I don't care if you drag me out.
I won't leave until Arnaldo pays!
And here I thought I was the stubborn one.
Looks like I have to go back
to the Ardientes.
No.
You've already done
what you were supposed to.
You've already exposed Arnaldo
for his crimes.
For now, let the law take care of this.
Mom…
We both know we'd never win
against the Ardientes in court.
And that's why
I'm working outside the law.
I'm following my own law,
what my heart says.
Because that's the only kind
that can't be bought
or intimidated.
And what are you going to do?
Help Arnaldo recover right after
having him jailed?
Mom, Arnaldo is…
He's the Ardientes' weakness.
Emilia's, Raul's,
and most especially Julio's.
I'll use Arnaldo so I can bring
all those criminals down.
Lily…
Isn't it enough
that you almost got killed?
Mom, it's not enough
that only Arnaldo took the fall.
Emilia has to go next.
And Raul.
Then, finally, Julio.
Mom…
Do we always have to fight about this?
Well, I won't stop if this is
what it takes to keep you safe.
Are you really going to stop me?
Are you really going to stop me
from taking vengeance
on the one who killed my father
and had you raped?
Yes!
It was me who got hurt,
so it should be my vengeance, not yours.
But she killed my father!
Emilia ruined my family!
And that's why she has to go next.
I'm not just doing this for us, Mom,
but for all the people who were
abused by the Ardientes!
I'll make sure whatever
suffering Emilia experiences
will surpass Arnaldo's.
She'll be abandoned by her husband,
forgotten by her son,
and disowned by her father.
She'll lose all her wealth
and even her name as an Ardiente.
She better prepare herself
because I'm not afraid of her.
Only death can get in the way
of my vengeance
against the Ardientes.
Only death.
[tense music playing]
Fine, then.
I won't stop you.
But, don't stop me with
what I'm about to do either.
Mom.
Please don't get yourself into danger.
I'll take the Ardientes down
the way I know how.
Mom.
[thudding]
What else do I have to do
to change this city?
What else?
What else?!
Anna?
Auntie.
You didn't leave?
I haven't finished what
I came here to do, Ms. Camia.
I can't rely on the law anymore.
I'm here now to help Ivy…
in any way I can.
Anna…
Every day,
my daughter risks
her life because of revenge.
I don't want you to do the same.
We'll fight the Ardientes
in a different way.
[pensive music playing]
[cell phone ringing]
-Ivy.
-Diego.
Ivy, we did everything right.
What else do we need to do
for things to change?
For there to be justice?
This is just the beginning, Diego.
I know prison isn't the
punishment waiting for Arnaldo.
Because I know he can escape that.
That's why I only crippled Arnaldo
to trigger the downfall of the Ardientes.
Can you blame me
for putting my trust in the law?
Diego, remember, the law here isn't fair.
It won't be that easy to get justice.
I won't give up.
I'm with you until the end.
Diego, it's not just me
who has faith in you…
the people of Ardiente
place their hopes on you.
My mother said she'll fight the Ardientes…
in the way she knows how.
If you can, protect my mother, Diego.
Don't worry, Ivy.
I'll keep her safe.
Thank you.
Guys, they're here. Gather around.
Over here.
Ms. Camia, we're here to ask for
a statement from your party
concerning the release of Mayor Arnaldo.
Thank you for accommodating us.
The message we want to send
is very important
for the people of Ardiente
and to the Ardiente family.
Mayor Arnaldo's release
is a slap in the face
to the people of Ardiente.
Like what they did with my husband's case,
they've proven once more that
they hold the law by the neck,
and that they can circumvent it.
This is unacceptable.
We must not let criminals
get swept into power.
Only one man has the right
to lead Poblacion Ardiente.
Only one man is ready to make
sacrifices for real change.
That's Diego Torillo.
Let's return the power to the people.
Long live the new Ardiente!
[all] To the new Ardiente!
Diego Torillo for change!
[all] Diego Torillo for change!
[applause]
As they say in the Olympics…
Let the games begin.
[chuckles]
For as long as we are
in the position of power,
no one can touch us.
So we have to strengthen our campaign.
We must win in this coming election.
It's as simple as that.
But, Papa, Arnaldo is a shell of himself.
His reputation is already ruined.
You know, Papa, why don't you
just make me run for governor?
I will take the position back.
I promise you.
[Julio laughing]
Have you forgotten?
People think you're dying of cancer.
Then, why don't we tell them
I was miraculously healed?
The people will even sympathize with me.
That way, they'll vote for
me. You can buy into anything.
Quit trying to play a part in this.
You already failed me once, Emilia.
And that will never happen again.
So, you're still willing
to take a risk on Arnaldo
even if he's going crazy?!
Arnaldo will be well again.
And the next time you say
that your son is going crazy,
I will send you to an asylum!
I will make Arnaldo well again.
And he will be the one to lead this town.
He will be the heir to my throne. Not you.
And certainly not that idiot, Diego.
I promise you this.
They would have to kill me first
before they can take my grandson down.
Friends, thank you so much
for supporting my event.
It was a huge success.
You know us.
Anything for the poor people of Ardiente.
[chuckles]
Congratulations
on the release of Mayor Arnaldo.
Well, that's expected to happen.
You know, whoever was behind
the plan to take Arnaldo down,
didn't do his or her homework very well.
My son was unlawfully arrested
and detained.
That's wrong. We all know that.
They didn't even think of that.
Oh.
So shallow of them not to think of that.
Order what you want.
[tense music playing]
You just think you've won, Emilia.
But everything that happened…
happened because of me.
It was all part of my plan.
[tense music continues]
I think we should get the fruit platter.
Ma'am, are you ready?
Ma'am, are you ready to order?
Why are you rushing me?
Is there a taxi meter?
Don't you know who I am?
I'm Emilia Ardiente.
You're unbelievable!
Wait. Can you just excuse me for a while?
-All right.
-Order what you want.
[tense music playing]
Guards!
-Guards!
-Ma'am.
Ivy's here. Search the whole place.
And when you find her, kill her.
We'll make it look like
an accident if she fights back.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Give me your gun.
Hurry!
[laughing]
Hey. Got you, Ivy.
Hmm…
Where are you?
I can smell you.
Hmm… That stinky perfume.
Ivy. Come on. Stop playing games with me.
Where are you?
I have your lipstick.
I know you're just here.
Where are you?
[laughing]
I know you're here.
Don't let me catch you.
Where are you?!
Come on. Ivy?
Ivy!
[tense music swelling]
Arnaldo. Arnaldo. Arnaldo.
You have to accept the fact
that Arnaldo is not well!
No one tells Julio Ardiente what to do!
I'll be able to protect you more
if I stay with the Ardientes.
Don't you dare go near my son!
We aren't done yet.
[Ivy] You don't deserve to die.
You deserve a fate worse than death.
An Ardiente never loses.
An Ardiente never dies!
[clatters]
Mrs. Emilia!
[screaming]
[theme music playing]